www.leonardoferrisi.com
linkedin.com/in/leonardo-ferrisi/

github.com/LeonardoFerrisi

Summary:

Motivated professional offering a diverse skill set in both Scientific Research, Software Engineering and the intersection of the two. Adds value to any organization in need of great collaboration, interpersonal and multitasking abilities. Meets tight deadlines. Rapid learner. Striving for nothing less than excellence in the endeavors I embark on.

Education: 09/2019 - Current

BS Double - Neuroscience / Computer Science Union College Class of 2023

Skills:

- Software Development and Design
- Design and Operation of Brain Computer Interfaces
- Signal Processing
- Teamwork, Collaboration, Team Leadership
- Data Collection and Analysis
- Technology Repair
- · Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning
- · Scientific Research, Technical Writing
- Operating Systems: Windows, MacOS, Linux

- Fluent in: Python, Java, Javascript, C, C++, R
- High Performance Computing / Parallel Computing
- Graphic Design
- Computational Neuroscience
- GIT and Version Control tools
- Video Production and Editing (Adobe, Vegas Pro)
- Task Automation
- Multitasking and Organization
- Project Planning
- Robotics Software Design

Student Research Technician

Experience:

06/2022 - 09/2022 CAM Lab, Union College - Schenectady, NY

Digital Technology Intern

GE Power - Schenectady, NY

 Collaborated with Technical Product Manager and other Upper-Level Management at GE Gas Power automate analytics backed decisions, problem resolution and applying software solutions to GE Power Worked with Professors and faculty regarding technical aspects of psychology research

Compiled and organized resource data

Neurotechnology Researcher

11/2021 - Current

National Center for Adaptive Neurotechnologies - Albany, NY

- Assisted with developing error handling and optimization of a system designed for rehab using evoked potentials conditioning
- Worked on updates and optimization of Brain Computer Interface for assistive communication
- Developed data science tools for quickly working with / processing data from sessions

Student Research Assistant

02/2021 - 06/2021

08/2021 - 06/2022

Feller Lab, Union College - Schenectady, NY

- Assisted in research regarding Neurophysiology in invertebrates, both collecting and studying microCT data from samples
- Developed documentation on lab related software

Digital Content Producer

09/2020 - 02/2021

The BCI Guys, Remote

 Contributed to content and video production for Foundations in Neurotechnology online course

Accomplishments:

- Dean's List, Union College 2021 Current
- Nu Rho Psi, Union College 2021 Current
- Summer Research Fellow, Union College 2021
- NY State Presidential Scholar Nominee, 2019
- National Hispanic Recognition Award, College Board 2019

Additional Skills:

• Proficient in Italian, English, Spanish

Leadership Experience:

• Founder, President, Union Neurotech

(www.unionneurotech.com)

09/2020 - Current

• Co - President, Union Rocket Club

09/2020 - 06/2022

• Council Chair, Minverva Program

03/2020 - 03/2022

 Board Member, LASO (Latin American

Student Organization)

09/2021 - 01/2022

 Founder, President, MARS (Mamaroneck Aeronautics and

Rocketry Society) 09/2017 - 06/2019